When José A. Villanueva Cleveland, heritage, honoree, induction ceremony.
He was born in Fort Rebo on here, down at the near west side of Cleveland.
He had been a partner in the Litigation Room in the Cleveland office of Baker
and Pass
Dettler since 1987.
Once again, see they linger behind me so I don't say everything.
But let me just type this, I don't know if she answered, I wish I did.
But I hear this son always refer to him as Elv F. May.
To me, that means the boss, he's the man, his son is waiting on the flag, and
he's the gentleman.
José A. Villanueva Cleveland, heritage, honoree, induction ceremony.
I got in when I got in.
You look at this group over here, Lord.
Oh my gosh.
So I'm going to stay consistent with the two-minute annotations I've observed
everyone else has done.
I consider it a high honor to disagree with you to celebrate this wonderful f***ing
help inductee.
In the Cleveland Hall of Fame, the Admiral Judge José Antonio Villanueva, a
friend of mine for 50 years.
Richard, you hear that?
Yeah.
You can't believe that he's known anybody for 50 years, right?
And what I'd like to do is briefly talk a little bit about his journey and talk
a little bit about his journey.
So this occasion is indeed a special one given the importance of what I think
the Cleveland Hall of Fame really represents,
and that is the most sacred of human values of liberty.
My wife, Marnie, and I have had the privilege of going to José in his beloved
white pecking,
and for me, she's always going to be a sweet 16 pecking.
And we've been blessed also to enjoy the friendship of his incomparable and
versatile son, Joshua.
As I and I grew up out of Riverside, Cleveland, in the neighborhood of St.
Patrick's Parish,
where we spent count as others playing baseball and basketball, engaging in
many civic and social activities and other things too, your honor.
And over at St. Patrick's Poppy House.
I've often described the judge as a man of history, and I think describing him
as such is really not an overstate.
In many ways, the journey of Judge Jose Villanueva is the journey of immigrant
America, which is the journey of America itself.
Born in the hills of Puerto Rico, initially living in projects in Gemesdon when
he came to America,
his honor rose to become the first Hispanic under 18th grade, the first
Hispanic in the history of this state
to be elected countywide domestic disservice in 1988.
You've got to remember that Ohio is the seventh, the seventh largest state in
America.
He remains to this day the only disbank, and let me repeat that, the only disbank
that we're elected to the general division of the county's court of this state.
And let me tell you a little bit about how he's done that.
In 2004, Judge Villanueva received 286,468 votes by 10 a.m. 286,468 votes.
That's a staggering number he's sure.
And in 2010, he came with approximately 1,000 votes of leading every judge in
the whole of the county.
Not bad from a boy from the hills of Puerto Rico.
A self-made man is sure.
And of a self-made man, Frederick Douglass once said,
"The idea of a self-made man is inextricably tied up with that of the American
Dream.
It is his image that has lured thousands of Americans to our shores, thousands.
The self-made man is he who comes from unpromising circumstances, who is not
born with privilege and wealth.
And yet by his own efforts, by pulling himself up by the bush,
he manages to become the great success that he is."
And that's America, too.
And that's the judge for South Dakota.
And that's how he is the best way known in our community, the judge or our
judge.
On the bench, she's distinguished himself with his extraordinary work ethic,
consistently ranked at the top of all accomplished judges in total jury trials
every year.
The judge consistently receives the endorsement of the Cleveland Plain Dealer.
He receives eyes and ratings of the professional legal organization in the
College of County,
including my own beloved Cleveland Bar Association.
And to be sure, his honor has been the arc of history in a positive direction.
The judge in my judgment is the personification of the certainty.
I've always admired how he has stood up for the last and the least, the voiceless.
Upon graduation, he immediately went into public service working for the
Cleveland Lake Lake Society, serving the poor.
He also served as commissioner for the Ohio Civil Rights Commission,
where he championed and offered policies for the handicapped and the victims of
sexual harassment.
He's only one of five judges, five judges of our 33 or 38 judges, who
volunteered to preside to
the Ohio County's mental health disabilities and development disabilities case
level.
On the community side, the judge's involvement and service to our community is
legendary.
His service includes the membership of my organization, Hispanic Ground Table,
numerous Hispanic organizations,
United Way, the Greater Cleveland Ground Table, the Cleveland Marshall Law
School,
you can read all those in his bio there.
Now to his heart.
This was a wonderful occasion to be sure, and I'm sure that he wishes that his
beloved mother,
going out loose, were here with us.
She was the lioness of the Van Vam of family, and we're blessed that there was
a sister here from Florida
who has many of those characteristics, loyalty, tender hearted yet courageous,
hardworking, and extraordinarily caring.
Traced and were not lost under his son.
Gayle Singer, the great running back of the Chicago Bears wrote a book,
entitled Lion Third, referring to God, family, and himself.
The judge's book, and my judgment should be entitled Five Lasts and For God,
Family, Friends, Hispanic Community,
and Anyone in Need, and then Him. I have personally observed many of his
countless acts of private charity and love,
and I won't tell you about it because I'll embarrass him.
The scripture teaches us, "Blessed are their pure in heart, for they will seek
out, to be sure, as they have blessed you."
At the same time, he had a warrior's heart on the athletic field, especially on
the basketball court, like my son did,
and on the baseball field where he always demonstrated grace under pressure and
leadership, and where he always evidenced the generosity gene.
I know that was the beneficiary, he always made me look good.
Let me close with one of my favorite church folk quotes, which is particularly
apropos to the judge.
"You make a living by what you get, but you make a life by what you do."
Genevieve Nueva has made an extraordinary life. I thank him. I thank God
Almighty.
And mostly I thank him for the treasure of his friendship.
Please help me give a round of applause to my dear friend, I go back to the
judge, Jose Athonio Viamo.
[APPLAUSE]